Hi.
In this awesome, I want to show you and explain how work with plan mode.
It's something you'll form with, so let's go.
The planning mode, it can help you to talk about some big, really complex tasks by breaking
them into smaller, easy-to-hando steps.
Instead of trying to describe everything in one long prompt, you can work with SCSI to
plan the process step by step.
This makes it easier to stay organized, track progress, and make sure each part of work is
done correctly, before moving to the next part, which is really important.
Also planning mode is available on all paid plans and currently no extra cost.
So if you're using wind source, free plan, you won't be able to use it unfortunately.
Okay, let's not talk about when you can use the planning mode, but the use cases.
Now, we can use it for multipart changes.
It's like features that touch many files or systems.
You can use it for big code changes, so when you do some big refactoring or updating a project
structure, when you use, when you're going to create some complex features, like you need
to work carefully and have some coordination between different parts of your project.
Okay, when you're going to create a new project, and you need a clear plan to understand
and change some unfamiliar code.
So this is all nice cases for using the planning mode.
How planning mode works, so you first need to start your goal.
So click the Plan icon I will show you, where to find it, you describe just your goal and
add any rules or requirements, for example, I don't know what libraries you want to use,
what you expect from a AI, etc.
Then you get the plan, because you can create a markdown plan with goals for you with all
the steps, challenges, and some dependencies, and it saves the file locally for the reference.
And then you execute it together with Cascade, you ask the scale to do some steps, update
the plan if needed, write progress, and at any moment you can pause or resume the plan.
So, let's now talk, and quickly, I will explain you some benefits of structured approach,
why you might need to use the plan mode, like what is a benefit for you, how it better
keeps the compact, the plan stay as a reference, that's how Cascade always remember your
goals, even for long past where you have no many files.
It's less mental effort, because breaking big tasks into smaller steps let you focus
on scene at time, so you don't think about the whole plan you've seen, it's some period
of time you just focus on like on a one step.
It more accurate, a clear roadmap helps you with missing some requirements or making some
mistakes.
And of course it's easy to adjust, you can update the plan as you go while still staying
aligned with your main goal, so, now let's switch to the wind source and I will show you,
there is an icon right here, you can enable the plan mode, okay, so you see it's a better
feature for now, but maybe when you see this video, it won't be better anymore, so when
you click on it, just remember that if you use a 3 plan, you won't be able to use this
feature, it's only for paid plans, okay, I prepared some prompt and I will explain what
you will do, it opens the password strength class, you see it's really a big class, it's
fine, but what I'm wondering that we have the check method which contains a really a lot
of check, and it's difficult to maintain this method, and I want to ask cascade to split
up this method on different methods for easier maintenance and testability, so I will
write my message, so I just explain the goal what you need to do, just split the logic
of check method from password strength checker class, I clearly say about the context
and what you need to do, into separate class methods for every check, update also unit
test with new changes because we have unit test, they also should be updated for the new
structure, and double check all logic and unit test works, this goal I will use a different
model, I will group it by provider, and for example we will use the close on that portal
because I am on 3L and I can, and I can use the premium model, and let's see what the result
will be, oh I have a bit of a factor, he's creating a plan, you see it's updating, you
can view the plan, let's click view, you see it's plan.md file, you see some modes that
user wants to split the logic, blah, blah, blah, blah, it's my request, this past
please, the cost analyze the class and check method logic, then identify distance which
can be separated, okay it's now updated, so let's click view it again, yeah, I can just
update it, so the first two plans, the next step is just refactor, move it check into
its own class method, separate step, the separate step for update unit test and separate
step, double check all the logic, so if we scroll down, we will see that he analyzes the
files, then he updated the plan, okay, he's say perfect, now we will refactor the password
check strange, so he's doing everything step by step, and we can review not everything
at once, but for example every step, so I was just close the plan, but now and we'll wait,
he will update it, okay we see he edited the password strange, oh, strange check, okay
we see the separate method for check command patterns, check symbols, check members, check
upper case, he also edited just doc the commentation, so it's really nice, it's much more
readable, it's much more readable, okay, let's see, there is a check function still, where
what he did, over here, he ran individual checks, but it's still a lot of code, so you've
got always kind of refactor it, and then proven, improve it, okay, he's finished, what
he did, he showed what files was refactor, okay, I split it up by six separate class
methods, he explains all the methods, or you can click on the method and see every method,
when you click on it, you scroll into the right position in your editor, then you hit
out here, that architecture, a bit, he enhanced unit test, and it's 15 new test cases,
so and all the test cases passing, so if we open the test cases, we'll see, okay, he
did, he split it up by the sections, like the just initialization, then individual check
methods, separate section, check lens method, some different use cases, for check lower
case, you see now we have much more test cases, it's much better for our project, and we
can be sure it works, okay, I will accept all the changes, as we open the plan, we can
also accept all the planches, we see he market everything is done, and when it back to our method,
yeah, we see all the changes, right zero, the old was deleted, it updated, so now let's
run the test command, if you forget what the test command, you can always open package
the JSON file, and see the scripts right here, and run this command, you can use NPM
run test, and we'll double check all the test works, and you see, this is the summary
of what test was run, and how it works, okay, I hope now you much more clear why you need
to use the planning mode, of course, if you have much bigger tasks, so it will be more
relevant, because it's really difficult to do everything at once, and you have ability
to review it, that by step, and see you in the next lesson, where I will explain you about
the context.